businesspundit.com 2016-06-08

# Privacy Policy - Business Pundit

Effective Date: December 6, 2016

**1\. Overview**

Welcome to the websites, applications and services provided by Business Pundit which includes without limitation www.businesspundit.com. This Privacy Policy, together with any documents it expressly incorporates by reference, governs your access to and use of the Sites on all platforms, whether accessed via web browser, mobile device, non-browser application, or e-mail, and to our paid subscription service. It does not apply to information collected by any third party, including through any application or content (including advertising) that may link to or be accessible from or on the Sites. In this Privacy Policy, “you” and “your” refer to you as the user of the Sites. “Business Pundit,” “we,” “us” and “our” refer to Business Pundit and our successors, partners, affiliates, subsidiaries and assigns.

Business Pundit takes privacy concerns seriously. This Privacy Policy outlines what information is collected when you visit the Sites. Please read this policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it.

The Sites contain links to websites hosted by third parties. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such third-party websites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave the Sites and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”) about you.

By using the Sites, you expressly accept and agree to be bound and abide by this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use, incorporated herein by reference. If you do not agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy, you may not access or use the Sites.

**2\. Changes to This Policy**

Business Pundit may at any time change this Privacy Policy to reflect any changes in our practices, service offerings, or market regulations. If the policy is updated, we will update the Effective Date at the top of the policy. Your continued use of Business Pundit after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check this Privacy Policy periodically for updates.

**3\. Information We Collect About You**

Business Pundit gathers information about its users mainly to enhance their experience on the Sites. This information is used to bring you content that is relevant to your interests. Additionally, Business Pundit, along with our advertising partners, collects information about you anonymously to provide you with targeted advertising messages that are catered to your location, interests, and the Sites behaviors. You can opt out of information gathering for advertising purposes with certain of our third-party partners below. This collected information includes 1) personal information you provide to us and 2) non-personal information we automatically collect through technology.

a. Personal Information You Provide To Business Pundit

When using the Sites, you may provide Business Pundit with PII, including but not limited to:

  * Personal contact information (name, zip code, e-mail address, and phone numbers)
  * User names (including social media user names)
  * Correspondence with Business Pundit staff
  * Billing Information (for paid Business Pundit products)
  * Contact information for Business Pundit event tickets

You may also provide information to be published or displayed on public areas of the Sites (“User Contributions”). Your User Contributions are posted on the Sites at your own risk. We cannot control the actions of other users of the Sites who view your User Contributions or with whom you may choose to share your User Contributions. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that your User Contributions will not be viewed by unauthorized persons.

If you are a Registered User and under the age of 18 years old, Business Pundit allows you to request removal of your User Contributions. For more information on the removal of User Contributions, see our Terms of Use.

You are not required to provide Business Pundit with any PII in order to use the Sites. Certain PII you provide to us can be updated through the account settings of registered users. PII that is collected is the sole property of Business Pundit, and that information is not distributed to third parties unless required by law.

b. Non-Personal Information We Automatically Collect About You

This type of information is collected anonymously through the use of technology, such as third-party cookies, web beacons, and other similar methods. No PII is collected through these methods. Non-personal information we automatically collect may include, but is not limited to:

  * Hardware/software information (geographic location, IP address, browser type, device type, operating system, bandwidth, etc.)
  * Analytics information (time spent on the Sites, number of pages viewed, referring web page, browsing information, social sharing, etc.)
  * Advertising information (type of ads seen, number of times ads were served, pages where the ads were served, etc.)
  * Information collected through cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies.

Some of the technology used includes but is not limited to:

Cookies: A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting, you may be unable to access certain parts of the Sites. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, the Sites will issue cookies when you direct your browser to the Sites.

Web beacons: The Sites content may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags and single-pixel gifs) that permit Business Pundit, for example, to count users who have accessed the Sites and for other related statistics, for example, recording the popularity of certain Sites’s content and verifying system and server integrity.

For more information on cookies, web beacons, and other similar technologies, please visit the [Internet Advertising Bureau’s Interactive Glossary](http://www.iab.net/research/1494).

c. Information Third-Parties Collect About You

This type of information is collected anonymously by approved third-party partners (such as online marketing firms, research companies, social media companies, ad targeting firms, and other partners). None of the information collected by these sources contains any PII. Information third parties collect about you includes but is not limited to:

  * Demographic information (gender, age, HHI, job title, interests, etc.)
  * Advertising information (clicks, interactions, post-impression performance data)
  * Social networking information (Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, etc.)
  * Research information (data collected from partners such as Nielsen, Comscore, Quantcast, etc.)

**4\. What Is Done With The Collected Information?**

Email Communications: Business Pundit may use the information that you submit to send you email communications, such as newsletters, breaking news, information about the Sites, alerts, and promotional messages from advertising partners.

Sites Analysis: Business Pundit uses the information collected through third-party sources to learn and analyze how the Sites are used. We use this information to enhance the Sites by making improvements based on the data collected.

Advertising: Display Ads are delivered from our adserver Google’s DoubleClick. We may use third-party advertising companies to collect data and/or serve ads when you visit our Sites. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, telephone number, or any PII) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to deliver targeted ads to you, your location, and your interests. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, visit [http://networkadvertising.org](http://networkadvertising.org/). We also use third-party ad platforms (such as Google AdSense, Google Ad Exchange, and The Rubicon Project) to deliver ads on our Sites and in our mobile apps. No PII is exchanged with any type of advertising message on Business Pundit. We also use a Data Management Platform (DMP) from Krux to store our anonymous data. To learn moure about Krux’s privacy policy please visit http://www.krux.com/krux_privacy/.

**5\. How We Share Information Collected**

There are very few specific circumstances when your information is shared outside of the company. These circumstances include but are not limited to:

  * If you post User Contributions or use social media applications in conjunction with the Sites, the information you submit (including your social media user name) is viewable to the public.
  * Business Pundit may need to disclose PII to comply with a judicial proceeding, a court order, or any other legal process.
  * We employ third-party services to distribute email newsletters, and these third-parties have access to specific information only for the purposes of fulfilling contracts on our behalf.
  * In the event Business Pundit goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of a portion of its assets, users’ PII will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred.

**6\. Email Policy**

Business Pundit is committed to complying with all U.S. privacy laws, such as the CAN-SPAM Act, and all other applicable privacy laws, such as Canada’s Anti-Spam Legislation, and it is our intention that our email communications be pursuant to such laws.

With the exceptions noted above, Business Pundit does not allow any third-party company to use your email address for commercial purposes without your expressed permission. We will send you newsletter communications, partner sponsorship messages, account alerts, and any other emails you have requested to receive. If you would like to opt-out of any specific newsletters or mailings, please login to your profile to change your newsletter settings.

**7\. Children Under 13**

Business Pundit is not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any information to or on Business Pundit Business Pundit does not knowingly target advertising to, or collect information from, children under the age of 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on the Sites or on or through any of its features, register on the Sites, use any of the interactive or public comment features on the Sites, or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, telephone number, email address or any screen name or user name you may use. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at feedback@businesspundit.com

**8\. Data Retention**

Your personal information is retained for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy.

**9\. Security**

Business Pundit uses commercially reasonable controls to safeguard data against unauthorized use and theft.

**10\. Third-Party Privacy and Opt-Out Information**

Business Pundit supports Do Not Track (“DNT”). If you enable DNT in your web browser, we stop collecting information about you consistent with the DNT setting. Below are links to the privacy policies of some of our partners and links to advertising opt outs to help you to further manage your online privacy. Google’s Doubleclick technology powers the adserving on Business Pundit. For more information about Google and DoubleClick’s privacy policy, go to [http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/). To opt-out from our DMP, please visit this link, http://www.krux.com/krux_privacy/consumer_choice/.

Google’s Ad Exchange help deliver ads on Business Pundit and its mobile apps.

Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) is part of the industry’s self-regulatory initiative. If you would like to opt out of third-party partners’ non-personal information tracking, visit the NAI opt-out section. Opting out does not mean you will not receive advertising on Business Pundit. It ensures that your non-personal information will not be automatically tracked by the sites you have opted out of.

**11\. Contact Us**

If you have any questions or suggestions for this Privacy Policy, please contact the editor of Business Pundit or email questions to feedback@businesspundit.com.
